Shahryar Soltanpour

CONTACT INFORMATION

e-mail: shahryar.soltanpour@gmail.com

mobile: $+1\ 403-827-9737$

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/soltanpour

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Birthday: May 8^{th} , 1997

ABOUT

I'm a skilled software engineer with nearly 4 years of working experience in Iranian top IT companies, and currently studying MSc of computer science (software engineering specialization) at UofC.

I'm interested in everything related to software engineering and big data technologies. Also, engaged with leadership skills and love to work as a team.

EDUCATION

• University of Calgary

MSc in Computer Science (Software Engineering) Under the supervision of Professor Robert Walker Jan. 2021 – Present

• University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2020

• GPA: 17.43/20

• last year GPA: 18.59/20

• Allame Helli 1 School

Diploma in Mathematics and Physics Discipline

2008 - 2015

• GPA: 19.91/20

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Software Engineer at *Divar*(Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2020) (1 Year and 4 Months):

Divar is the leading application for online classified ads, and one of the most prominent Iranian companies in Information Technology, having more than 40 million users. In Divar, we were developing using Go and Python languages and Django as the framework. Our deployment was being done using Kubernetes. My main responsibilities during my career are listed below:

- Designing system for new features, by writing 'design docs' and implementing them.
- Development of designed features, create merge requests, and deploy them on production servers.
- Maintaining services. As the owner of some services, I had to make sure that my services are operating properly 24/7.
- Reviewing codes. As the system owner, I was responsible to evaluate merge requests on my owned services then merge and deploy them.
- Designing system for new features, by writing 'design docs' and implementing them.
- Member of the interview committee. Attending interviews with new people who wanted to enter the company, and helping the company hire the best software engineers.
- Software Enginner at *Pegah Co. (known as Tapsell)*] (Sep. 2017 Aug. 2019) (2 Years): Tapsell is the leading company in the online advertising industry in Iran.
 - *Mediaad*(Jun. 2018 Aug. 2019):

During my experience in Mediaad, I implemented a video player platform, helping website owners to upload and stream their video files, see statistics for each video and also earn money by showing advertisements. I also implemented the dashboard of this platform using Angular 6.

I also implemented some features in Mediaad platform, such as retargeting feature. I worked with Spring Boot and Kotlin and I got to work with big data processing tools such as Kafka streams, Elastic Search, Cassandra DB and I got familiar with Apache Spark.

• Backtory(Jan. 2018 - Jun. 2018):

Backtory is a CDN, storage and streaming service provider startup. During my experience in Backtory, I worked with Spring Boot framework using Kotlin as the programming language and I became skilled in them. I also learned and worked with HAProxy and Nginx as web servers and load balancers.

• Software Engineering Intern at Rahnema College (July 2017-Aug. 2017) (2 Months) :

In this cycle of Rahnema College our team launched Unagi, a location based social network application. In this project, I focused on iOS and Android application development using React-Native and React-Redux and I also focused on server-side development using Node. JS Express framework. This project gave me a chance to get to know and apply the Scrum methodology and Git VCS.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

• Graduate Research(May 2021 - Present):

The subject of my research is more about working on multilingual codes specially used in industry, and also maintaining a change propagation framework written in CSharp. This framework supports multiple languages such as Java, CSharp, Python and Transact-SQL.

Under the supervision of **Professor Robert Walker**.

• Undergraduate Research(Jul. 2019 - Oct. 2019):

Real-time verification and evaluation of algorithms efficiency in distributed actor based systems

Using java language to compile and run Rebeca codes with different policies and measure some metrics to find the best algorithm.

Rebeca (Reactive Objects Language) is an actor-based language with a formal foundation, designed in an effort to bridge the gap between formal verification approaches and real applications. It can be considered as a reference model for concurrent computation, based on an operational interpretation of the actor model. It is also a platform for developing object-based concurrent systems in practice.

Under the supervision of Dr. Fatemeh Ghassemi.

• Blockchain, CryptoCurrency and Digital Currencies

I've passed $Introduction\ to\ Cryptocurrency\ course$ as my master's degree course and I got the mark 20/20. During this course, I studied several essays about Bitcoin, Ethereum and blockchain and did some computer assignments to use make Bitcoin transactions in P2PKH and P2SH modes and broadcast them to the blockchain. I also did some computer assignments to make a simple application using Solidity, web3.js and Truffle framework in order to deeply understand smart contracts.

Under the supervision of **Dr. Behnam Bahrak**.

Honors and Awards

- \bullet Ranked 241^{st} (regional rank), and 368^{th} (national rank) in the National Universities Entrance Examination among more than $318{,}000$ contestants, 2015
- Ranked 3^{rd} among Undergraduate Students in Software Engineering College and winner of FoE (Faculty of Engineering) prize, University of Tehran (2015-2017)

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

- Implement a web-based free lancing application for Internet Engineering course. Using Java for back-end and React for front-end development. (Source Code: Backend and Frontend)
- Implement a crawler and data-analysis on Lululemon website as the main project of Datamining and Social Netowrk course using Scrapy, Gephi and Networkx. (Source Code: Lululemon-Ambassadors
- Implement Splitwise application using smart contracts using technologies such as Truffle, Solidity language and web3.js (Source Code: *Splitwise*)
- Implement a compiler for an actor based language named Atalk in compiler design course. (Source Code: Atalk)

• Implement a location based social netowrk named Unagi during Rahnema College internship. Backend was coded using NodeJs Express and Android and iOS applications were coded using React Native. (Source Code: *Backend* and *Frontend*)

Volunteer experience

President of Computer Science Graduate Society of UofC

August 2021 - Present

As the president of CSGS, I attend in the computer science Department meetings, have interview with faculty candidates, and hold events for graduate students.

Mentor in Summer of Code event at University of Tehran

Jul. 2018 - Sep. 2018

In the annual event of "Summer of Code" at the University of Tehran, I was the mentor of a team consisting of 5 students. The team was working to implement a storage provider service named UT Cloud. As the mentor, I taught them backend technologies such as Spring Boot and Nginx. Besides, we used the scrum methodology to make the mentees familiar with agile methodologies.

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIP

SENG 300 (Introduction to Software Engineering)

Winter 2022

Instructor: Dr. Robert Walker

Responsible for grading assignments and group projects for 3 tutorial sessions (Each containing 28 students)

SENG 300 (Introduction to Software Engineering)

Winter 2021

Instructor: Dr. Robert Walker

Responsible for grading assignments and group projects for 2 tutorial sessions (Each containing 28 students)

Internet Engineering

Spring 2020

Instructor: Dr. Ehsan Khamespanah

Chief TA of the course. Responsible for managing all course projects to be designed, delivered and graded.

Systems Analysis and Design

Spring 2019

Instructor: Dr. Fatemeh Ghassemi

Chief TA of the course. Responsible for managing course projects, quizzes and homeworks.

In addition, I have 9 more experiences of being TA in courses such as Compiler design, Artificial Intelligence, statistics and data structure and algorithms.

Language Skills

Persian: Native

English: Advanced - TOEFL: 104 (R:28 L:25 S:26 W:25)

SOFTWARE SKILLS

SpringBoot, Kotlin, Java: 4/5

Python, Django: 4/5

Golang: 3/5 KafkaStreams: 3/5

NoSQLs(MongoDB, Cassandra, Redis): 3/5

ElasticSearch: 3/5 Kubernetes: 4/5 MySql:3/5 Docker: 4/5 Antlr: 3/5

Apache Spark: 1/5 Angular: 2.5/5 C, C++: 3/5 Javascript: 4/5 React,React Native,React Redux : 3/5

Node.JS: 2/5Tools: Git, \LaTeX

Agile Methodology: Scrum, XP

Simulation: Multisim, Modelsim, Quartus II, Pspice, Logic Gate Simulator